Guangzhou, China, known as the world's factory,
has the largest concentration of apparel firms in the nation.
Many workers there are migrants from Hubei Province.
They live in an area called Hubei Village.
The village now faces an unprecedented crisis
due to the spread of the coronavirus.
The young generation is the same.
Hube's capital of Wuhan is where the coronavirus infections began to spread.
Since the lockdown there, discrimination and prejudice against Hube natives
have made life even harder.
To survive, some work under harsh conditions, often sacrificing sleep.
business owners are also in a tight spot
While Hurley to recover from the coronavirus, China is frantically rebuilding its economy and its manufacturing sector.
This episode follows the front lines of its apparel industry.
One Joe is one of China's largest cities.
Its many skyscrapers are a testament to the country's rapid economic development.
A unique area exists in the center of the city surrounded by high-rise buildings.
The district is known as Kan-Likun.
Since China's economic reform, the apparel industry has boomed,
making this neighborhood one of China's largest manufacturing bases.
The narrow, web-like streets stretching in all directions are packed with small buildings.
The district has more than 30,000 apparel-related factories.
The entire production process, from printing designs on fabric to sharing and sewing, can
be performed right here.
Completed products are immediately delivered to locations throughout China and the entire
world.
Of the roughly 200,000 migrant workers here, some 90% hail from Hubei province.
It was the many INS, stores and restaurants targeting workers from Hubei that caused this area
to be known as Hubei Village. Hubei natives, known for their strong sense of solidarity,
have supported each other in this new land and built a unique community.
In January 2020, Wuhan was locked down due to the spread of the coronavirus.
The infection quickly spread in Guangzhou, and Hubei Village, known for its close ties to Wuhan, was soon restricted.
Work only resumed in late March, but by then the domestic economy had suffered and global demand had plunged.
Many factories and stores in the village went out of business.
Notices of factories and equipment for sale can be seen posted all over town.
Thousands of workers have lost their jobs,
and many are now scraping by on Daylabor.
At 7 a.m., workers flock to a narrow alley known as the Jobseeker's Street
in front of the police station in Hubei Village.
Factory managers recruit workers with clothing samples in hand.
Most of the available work is Daylabor,
and long-term contracts are now rare.
The average pay is just $30 USD a day,
nearly half than what they would make in a long-term contract.
Yet people fight over the vital opportunity to work.
Workers are transported directly to the factories.
Fifty nine-year-old champion manages a factory that makes women's clothing.
Work, content, wages and hours are negotiated on the spot by both parties.
Chen named her factory Hangu after her beloved granddaughter.
She migrated here from Hubei 20 years ago, along with her husband Lang Yong.
They saved money from street vending and part-time jobs and opened their own factory 10 years ago.
我作全球的,我自己本來我的蛋糊飾
去他們作外蛋的,我不做中國人的
歐美啊,新西蘭啊,像西馬太亞,韓國啊,伊朗啊
阿拉伯啊,沙特啊,什麼敵拜啊,什麼地方都做
今年日到這種情況以後,今年我們中國就封關了嘛
封關就國外的人也不得進來呀,我們這邊就根本就沒有外蛋
had over 20 employees making more than 2,000 pieces
of clothing a day, mostly orders from overseas.
But now, it gets just a few orders
from domestic companies.
Garment factories nearby are also suffering
from a sharp decrease in international clients,
making it difficult for them to survive.
Until recently, the garment industry in Guangzhou depended strongly upon workers from
Hubei Province.
However, all that is now changing.
At 10 pm, the streets are still crowded with job seekers.
The industry now focuses on the domestic market, but competition has only intensified.
With online shopping as the mainstream in China, fashion trends change at lightning speed.
Factories get mass orders under extremely short delivery terms for items expected to become
popular.
Speed is of the essence, so the factories operate around the clock.
Day laborers now work late into the night.
Chen is also forced to operate her factory 24-7 to meet demand.
As soon as she receives orders, Chen goes out looking for temporary laborers.
The key is getting workers who are highly skilled.
I'm going to go.
Wow.
This is not going to be long.
This is going to be a long time.
I'm going to go to the next one.
Chen brings in a female worker.
49-year-old seamstress Dong Shang-yu divorced her husband 12 years ago
and moved along with her children from a farming village in Hu Bay.
Although a veteran of the industry,
she launched her job due to the pandemic
and now works day labor for several factories.
She says it's the first time she's worked like this
in over a decade of experience in the garment industry.
No matter how bad the wages or work conditions may be, laborers say it's difficult to find work outside of who pay village.
They are still in the same situation.
Day laborers now suffer from the expanding ripples of the pandemic.
Fears competition, low wages, and more than 15 work hours a day.
Despite these conditions, Hu Bay Village still represents the last stronghold from migrant workers.
It's 10pm.
Six hours later, Dung finally finishes work and heads home.
She's observed an increase in crime in Hubei Village.
He lives in a room of a rundown three-story building.
Do you want to take a look at this?
Yes.
I can't help it.
I'll take a look.
Due to the severe slump and demand in the apparel industry,
some factory owners with no other course of action are sitting on the streets hoping for orders.
Signs read seeking clients.
The decline of a peril has also impacted other industries in Hubei village.
The Yongsheng, a local inn, has more than 30 rooms.
The owners, young shambing and his wife, Bai Chun-jie, were born into farming families
in Hubei province.
They came here 10 years ago, introduced by friends.
Seeing an opportunity in the hotel industry,
they borrowed $100,000 from relatives
to rent the building and open their in.
But business is tough.
The number of visitors has plummeted
due to the weakening of the apparel industry.
The 100 plus ends in Hubei Village
are now fighting over limited guests.
March to May is peak production season for summer clothing.
Usually many buyers and laborers flock to Hubei Village during this period.
Due to the pandemic, few guests show up even in June.
A potential guest drops in.
Even at half-off, they couldn't manage to convince the man to stay.
Staying open is a huge financial burden for them.
Rent alone comes to around $5,000.
There are also utilities and management costs to pay.
Your losses have already exceeded $20,000 this year.
Meanwhile, seamstress and single mother Dong Sheng Yu
continues working one day labor gig after another.
She goes out for an all night job again.
Dong works nonstop to save money for her 30-year-old son's
marriage.
She made just $30 for her long night of work.
No, no, no, no, no.
To earn as much as possible,
Dungo's straight to another factory.
Her workday can be as long as 18 hours,
while physically strenuous.
For Dung, Hubei village is an irreplaceable source of income.
With the conditions ceasing to improve,
Discord has spread even among the typically harmonious
village residents.
I'm here to help you.
Look, look outside.
Look outside.
There are many people who can find you.
It's hard to find you.
I want you to keep your life.
The goods are only for you.
You can't get them.
How do you sell them?
They sell them.
I don't know.
I have a business.
There is no such thing as a hand.
The house is made of paper,
and the hand is made of paper.
We all have to eat.
This is called the place.
It's 7 yuan.
The price of this is 2 yuan.
The shop is called the Yufuara.
It's about 1 yuan.
It's worth it.
The Yufu restaurant is not that expensive.
It's not that expensive.
They have been going back to the factory.
We have to do the back work.
For example, we have to make a simple and simple
and simple and simple.
Then we have to make a natural.
The people of the factory are going to learn it.
They will come and work.
They will work.
What is this?
They have a little responsibility.
They have a burden.
They have no power.
We are the workers of the labor market.
The labor market is very new to China.
This is all the work.
You are also a labor worker.
You are the workers of the labor market.
We are the workers of the labor market.
We are very old-fashioned.
We are the most basic.
We are very advanced.
We are rich in wealth.
We are happy.
But labor workers are what?
Factory owners and laborers are all trying to eat out a living.
one day at a time.
In mid-April, factory owners in Guangzhou demanded assistance measures from the local government,
such as the lowering or exemption of rent.
Authorities cracked down on demonstrators.
Some support measures were later provided, but did little to help factory owners.
Hotel owner, Young, is three months behind in rent due to the drop in guests.
His landlord from Guangzhou has been demanding payment.
One day, the landlord storms in.
The argument continued for two hours with no compromise from either side. Yang decided to seek advice from the police.
After the police intervened, Yang's monthly rent payment was reduced by $1,000, one fifth of the total rent.
The agreement applies to the amount in a Rears up to October 2020.
In hopes of gaining extra income, Yang's wife, Bai, talked to a relative who works in a peril.
Yes, I have been working with him since I was young.
I've been working with him.
I don't want to work in the kitchen.
I have been working with him for a few days.
I don't want to work with him.
If I don't want to work with him,
I'll have to go out and work.
Yang and his wife hope to make a decision by September.
They'll be forced to choose between continuing to run the inn,
or closing it and moving back to Hubei Province.
Factory owner Chen and her husband are still hoping for recovery
in overseas demand and the domestic economy.
I feel like I'm a newbie.
I feel like we're all in China now.
And after we've all been in China,
Don't plan to continue working in Hubei Village until her only son gets married.
I can't believe it.
I'm not doing it right now.
It's just a little bit of a shame.
I can't believe it.
Migrant workers debate whether to stay here
or return to Hu Bay.
But no amount of contemplation will give a clear answer.
With no end in sight for the pandemic,
Dung's long days of labor continue.
The workers remain in the so-called world's factory.
But the longer they hold out,
The farther the coronavirus seems to separate them from their dreams.